<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Adam Dymitruk</title>
    <link>/categories/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Adam Dymitruk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Filtering by Author Name</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-07-18-filtering-by-author-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-07-18-filtering-by-author-name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s unbelievable the kind of attention something simple can get. I&amp;rsquo;m still suprised at how many up-votes &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4259996/how-can-i-view-a-git-log-of-just-one-users-commits&#34;&gt;this answer&lt;/a&gt; is getting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Git, filtering by author name is easy. Most people simply use the name of the committer that they are interested in. However, it&amp;rsquo;s a little more powerful due to the fact that the author option on git log is actually interpreted as regex. So for looking for commits by &amp;ldquo;Adam Dymitruk&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just type &lt;code&gt;git log --author=&amp;quot;Adam&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; or use the last name if there more contributors with the same first name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branch-per-Feature</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-02-05-branch-per-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2012 22:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2012-02-05-branch-per-feature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dymitruk-model&#34;&gt;The Dymitruk Model&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the methodology defined below is the most effective way to leverage the power of Distributed Version Control Systems - specifically Git. This work is the result of an in depth analysis of Continuous Intergration and the notion of &lt;em&gt;responsible&lt;/em&gt; Continuous Delivery. The inherent risks that de facto CI and CD introduce are mitigated by what others now refer to as &amp;ldquo;The Dymitruk Model&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;features-are-small&#34;&gt;Features are small&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Old-school branch-per-feature meant that branches were large and long living to avoid having to integrate because it was a pain. This was a vicious circle as the feature would diverge further and further from other features or the mainline. Features should be as atomic as possible and your development process should abide by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open/closed_principle&#34;&gt;Open Close Principle&lt;/a&gt;. Features should be small.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
