<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bash on Adam Dymitruk</title>
    <link>https://blog.dymitruk.com/categories/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bash on Adam Dymitruk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.dymitruk.com/categories/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scripting for Fun</title>
      <link>https://blog.dymitruk.com/posts/2012-07-20-scripting-for-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.dymitruk.com/posts/2012-07-20-scripting-for-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;minecraft&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.dymitruk.com/images/minecraft.png&#34; style=&#34;float:left;margin:0 10px 10px 0&#34; markdown=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing minecraft a couple of nights a week for about 40 minutes each time with my son. This seems to be a trend even for very young children. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too long before I found myself running a server so that we could play together with our friends (We even setup a trello board for our missions and projects!). It&amp;rsquo;s much more fun to work together and build something. Discovering new places and building contraptions, houses and other things is very stimulating for a young mind - as well as my old mind. This generation has so much more at their disposal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filtering by Author Name</title>
      <link>https://blog.dymitruk.com/posts/2012-07-18-filtering-by-author-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.dymitruk.com/posts/2012-07-18-filtering-by-author-name/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s unbelievable the kind of attention something simple can get. I&amp;rsquo;m still suprised at how many up-votes &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4259996/how-can-i-view-a-git-log-of-just-one-users-commits&#34;&gt;this answer&lt;/a&gt; is getting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Git, filtering by author name is easy. Most people simply use the name of the committer that they are interested in. However, it&amp;rsquo;s a little more powerful due to the fact that the author option on git log is actually interpreted as regex. So for looking for commits by &amp;ldquo;Adam Dymitruk&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just type &lt;code&gt;git log --author=&amp;quot;Adam&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; or use the last name if there more contributors with the same first name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
